A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Women's studies: its origins, its organization and its prospects: Wesleyan University (Reports 010194), 1976 (Box 413)
  Higher Education & Research
  L71-26.
  PAPER Conference (1977 Feb. 22: New York, N.Y.)
  Women's studies -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States -- Curricula
- Issues affecting world peace and welfare (Reports 010195), 1979 (Box 413)
  Handwritten notes on International Division Conference, March 21, 1979.
  16, 10 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  International relations; World politics
- Reporting on the ID conference to the International Committee (Reports 010196), 1979 (Box 413)
  Hastily drafted notes on the International Division Conference, March 1979.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Congresses
- Plans for International Division Conference March 21-24, 1979 (Reports 010197) (Box 413)
  3 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration
- Current program reports and other documents for the regional staff conference in governmental planning, organization, and administration, April 14-17 (Reports 010198), 1967 (Box 413)
  60 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Central planning -- Middle East; Public administration -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Workshop for emerging community development corporations (Reports 010199), 1984 (Box 414)
  Workshop held, March 22-24, 1984.
  Urban Poverty program/Program Related Investments
  L84-45.
  Community development corporations
- A summary of the March 13, 1975 Mexico City meeting on Mexican-American border problems (Reports 010200) (Box 414)
  Borderlands -- United States; Borderlands -- Mexico
- Summary of "Seminar on Ford Foundation Public Management Program in East and Southern Africa" organized by the Nairobi field office, held in Dar es Salaam, August 19-22 (Reports 010201), 1973 (Box 414)
  L73-306.
  PAPER Conference (1973 Aug. 19-22: Dar es Salaam, Tanzania)
  Public administration
- Foundation-wide review of public management (in the developing countries) (Reports 010202), 1973 (Box 414)
- Management development - regional approach (Reports 010203), 1973 (Box 414)
  Executives -- Training of
- Retrospective overview of Foundation public management program in Eastern and Southern Africa (Reports 010204), 1973 (Box 414)
  L73-306
- Developing public management in Kenya (Reports 010205), 1973 (Box 414, Reel R-9302)
  Executives -- Training of -- Kenya; Public administration -- Kenya
- Public management development in Tanzania (Reports 010206), 1973 (Box 414)
  Discussion of the importance of public enterprise to Tanzania's national development objectives.
  Public administration -- Tanzania
- Tanzanian approaches to improved financial management of the public directly productive sector: with special reference to the Institute of Finance Management (Reports 010207), 1973 (Box 414)
  Discussion of financial management in the context of Tanzanian goals and realities.
  Public administration -- Tanzania -- Congresses
- A country study of management development in Botswana (Reports 010208), 1973 (Box 414)
  Paper presented at the Ford Foundation Seminar on Public Management, 19th-22nd August, 1973.
  21 p. + appendices.
  Public administration -- Botswana
- Address to the Ford Foundation seminar at Dar es Salaam on the dimensions of the management development problem in Africa (Reports 010209), 1973 (Box 414)
  Discussion of the importance of politics to management development in Africa.
  Dimensions of the management development problem in Africa
  Public administration -- Africa
- Reforming the public enterprises in Africa Nairobi (Reports 010210), 1970 (Box 414)
  Public administration -- Africa; Government business enterprises -- Reform -- Africa
- Parastatal organisations in Uganda (Reports 010211), 1973 (Box 414)
  Public administration -- Uganda; Government business enterprises -- Uganda
- Ford Foundation public management program in East and Southern Africa: Country paper: Zambia (Reports 010212), 1973 (Box 414)
  Discussion of the parastatal as an important part of the Zambian national economy.
  Public administration -- Zambia; Government business enterprises -- Zambia
- Ford Foundation: Review of public management (Reports 010213), 1973 (Box 414)
- An evaluation of the accelerated cereal production project in Tunisia and the related Ford Foundation grant to CIMMYT 1968-1970 (Reports 010214) (Box 414)
  42 p. -- 28 cm.
- Review of U.S. Rural Poverty and Resources program, 1986 June. (Reports 010215) (Box 414)
  Prepared for discussion at the June 1986 meeting of the Urban and Rural Poverty Committee of the Board of Trustees.
  Board of Trustees; United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  77 leaves.
  Rural poverty and resources in the United States
  Natural resources -- Management; Rural development -- United States; Water -- Management
- Program notes on Pakistan's rural development activities (Reports 010216), 1975 (Box 414)
  L75-167
  PAPER Conference (1976 Jan. 12-14: Singapore)
  Rural development -- Pakistan
- India: the Foundation's program in agriculture and rural development (Reports 010217), 1976 (Box 414)
  L75-167.
  8 p. + appendices.
  Rural development -- India; Agriculture -- India
- Rural development program Ford Foundation Bangladesh (Reports 010218), 1976 (Box 414)
- Thailand country notes and Ford Foundation program for rural development in Thailand (Reports 010219), 1976 (Box 414)
  Rural development -- Asia
- Toward a provincial level grants program in the service of Philippine rural development (Reports 010220), 1975 (Box 414)
  19 p. + attachment.
- Rural development in Indonesia (Reports 010221), 1975 (Box 414)
- Notes on rural development in Middle East and Africa (Reports 010222), 1975 (Box 414)
  Rural development -- Middle East; Rural development -- Africa
- Issues: Human and institutional capacities for rural development (Reports 010223), 1976 (Box 414)
  12 p. + tables.
- Background notes for Villa de Leyva, Colombia April 26-28, 1976 Social Science meeting (Reports 010224) (Box 414)
  The background notes are excerpts from grants: terminal evaluations, financial and narrative reports etc. ...
  L75-245.
  PAPER Conference (1976 Apr. 26-28: Villa de Leyva, Colombia)
  Social sciences -- Latin America
- Rapporteurs' reports from individual sessions of April 26-28, 1976, Villa de Leyva, Colombia, social science meeting (Reports 010225) (Box 414)
- Health care for poor women in Brazil, Portugal, and the United States (Reports 010226), 1981 (Box 414)
  Medical care -- Women -- Brazil; Medical care -- Women -- Portugal; Medical care -- Women -- United States
- The crises of the European universities and the crises of European culture (Reports 010227), 1968 (Box 415)
  48 p. + attachment.
  Education, Higher -- Europe; European universities
- A five year program for the improvement and education for Negroes (Reports 010228), 1963 (Box 415)
  Education -- Minorities; African Americans -- Education
- Program possibilities for the disadvantaged in vocational education for "blue-sky" discussions (Reports 010229), 1966 (Box 415)
  Education and Research/Public Education
  11 p. + appendix.
  Poor -- Vocational guidance
- Comprehensive school improvement program (Reports 010230), 1972 (Box 415)
  School improvement programs; Improvement of schools
- Grants for vocational and technical education (Reports 010231), 1967 (Box 415)
  Vocational education -- Research grants; Technical education -- Research grants
- Education Program: planning budget for fiscal year 1965-1966-1967 (Reports 010232), 1964 (Box 415)
  12 p.: table -- 28 cm.
  Adult education -- United States -- Finance; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Program planning budget report as of March 31 (Reports 010233), 1966 (Box 415)
  13 p.: principally tables -- 28 cm.
  Educational assistance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Evaluation
- Teacher education programs (Reports 010234), 1965 (Box 415)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Trip to Atlanta and Houston (Reports 010235), 1966 (Box 415)
  Voyages and travels -- Atlanta -- United States; Voyages and travels -- Houston (Tex.) -- United States
- Vocational and Technical Education Program (Reports 010236), 1966 (Box 415)
  14 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Vocational education -- United States; Technical education -- United States; Technical institutes -- United States; Vocational teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Schools, vocational and technical education, and education generally (Reports 010237), 1963 (Box 415)
  Vocational education -- United States; Technical education -- United States
- Compensatory education (Reports 010238), undated (Box 415)
  Compensatory education -- United States
- Breakthrough in teacher education (Reports 010239), 1967 (Box 415)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- The impact of forty-two Ford Foundation grants in teacher education on the recipients, neighboring institutions, school districts, and state certification requirements (Reports 010240), 1964 (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Twenty-nine million for what? (Reports 010241), undated (Box 415)
  Innovation in education; Education -- Ford Foundation role
- The Foundation and the foreign student "problem" (Reports 010242), 1968 (Box 415)
  15 p. + attachment.
  Students, Foreign
- Facilities loan fund (Reports 010243), 1964 (Box 415)
  Facilities loan fund -- United States
- The Volkswagen Foundation (Reports 010244), 1965 (Box 415)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Germany; Endowment of research -- Germany
- American higher education in 1990 (Reports 010245), 1967 (Box 415)
- Causes and effects in accreditation (Reports 010246), undated (Box 415)
  Accreditation (Education) -- United States
- The college admissions problem in perspective (Reports 010247), undated (Box 415)
  Universities and colleges -- Admission -- United States
- Conference of ministers of education of European member states on access to higher education (Reports 010248), 1967 (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- Europe -- Congresses
- Conversations in Europe, 22 June, 1964 to 11 (Reports 010249) (Box 415)
  Conversation -- Europe; European conversation
- Performance of durum varieties in the regional nurseries (Reports 010250), undated (Box 415)
  Agriculture -- Middle East; Wheat production -- Middle East
- Education opportunities for Negroes (Reports 010251), 1966 (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- African Americans; African Americans -- Education -- United States
- The Ford Foundation, education, and television (Reports 010252), 1966 (Box 415)
  Television in education -- United States
- Graduate studies at the University of Wisconsin (Reports 010253), 1966 (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education -- Wisconsin; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work
- New students, new problems (Reports 010254), undated (Box 415)
  New students, new problems; Education systems; Democratization of education
- Notes on the planning of HSIU (Reports 010255), undated (Box 415)
  Planning of HSIU -- Ethopian universities; Education, Higher -- Ethiopia
- Patterns of development in higher education (Reports 010256), 1965 (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Patterns of development in higher education
- Planning for Foundation activities in Europe (Reports 010257), 1968 (Box 415)
  Planning for Foundation activities -- Europe; Endowments -- Program-related investments -- Europe
- Poverty and education (Reports 010258), 1964 (Box 415)
  Poverty -- United States; Poor -- Education -- United States
- Present state of universities (Reports 010259), 1968 (Box 415)
  Universities and colleges -- Evaluation -- United States; Education, Higher -- Evaluation -- United States
- Problems of selection in developing societies -- an inquiry (Reports 010260), 1968 (Box 415)
  Education and state -- Developing countries; Educational change -- Developing countries; Education -- Research -- Developing countries; Educational assistance -- Developing countries
- Program planning budget - discussion (Reports 010261), 1965 (Box 415)
  Program budgeting; Ford Foundation -- Finance -- Management
- Travel diary Ankara, Istanbul, Cairo, Paris (Reports 010262), 1967 (Box 416)
  76 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical education -- Turkey; Vocational education -- Turkey; Teachers -- Training of -- Turkey; Educational assistance -- Turkey
- Travel diary Ethiopia and Abid (Reports 010263), 1968 (Box 416)
  41 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Medical colleges -- Ethiopia; Medical colleges -- Cte d'Ivoire; Medical sciences -- Study and teaching -- Ethiopia; Cte d'Ivoire; Higher education and state -- Ethiopia; Higher education and state -- Cte d'Ivoire
- Travel diary: Europe: February 2 - 25, 1967: draft (Reports 010264) (Box 416)
  62 p. -- 28 cm.
  Education, Higher -- Europe; International education -- Europe; International education -- United States
- Travel diary: Europe: April 12 - 21, 1967 draft (Reports 010265) (Box 416)
  28 p. -- 28 cm.
- Trip diary: O.E.C.D. Center (Reports 010266), 1967 (Box 416)
  86 p.
  Economic development
- Travel diary Yugoslavia (Reports 010267), 1967 (Box 416)
  43 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Educational change -- Yugoslavia; Education -- Research -- Yugoslavia; Education and state -- Yugoslavia; Educational assistance -- Yugoslavia
- Travel diary for Puerto Rico trip - March 13-16 (Reports 010268), 1967 (Box 416)
  Puerto Rico
- Trip diary: American Samoa, from October 4, 1966 to October 12 (Reports 010269) (Box 416)
  Education -- American Samoa; Education and state -- American Samoa; Educational assistance -- American Samoa; Teachers -- Training of -- American Samoa
- Visit to Compton College, Los Angeles - Wednesday, November 6 (Reports 010270), 1968 (Box 416)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Compton Coolege -- United States
- Nations with fully developed school systems (Reports 010271), undated (Box 416)
  Education; Nations with fully developed school systems; Developed school systems; School systems
- A report to the Ford Foundation on law and social justice in Brazil (Reports 010272), 1977 (Box 416)
  08000820
  Center for Studies of Contemporary Culture (CEDEC)
  Support for applied research in labor unionization and urban violence.
  45 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Report to the Ford Foundation: law and social justice in Brazil
  Law -- Research -- Brazil; Public law -- Brazil; Social justice -- Brazil; Social legislation -- Brazil
- Recommendations to the Federal Department of Agriculture for monitoring and evaluation of major third plan projects, Jan. (Reports 010273), 1975 (Box 416)
  Consultant report to help the Department to develop the monitoring and evaluation system for agricultural projects in the Third National Development Plan.
  Agricultural development projects -- Nigeria
- The M.A. programs in SIDEC: report of evaluation for Ford Foundation (Reports 010274), 1975 (Box 416)
  43 p. + appendices.
  Education, Higher -- Evaluation
- Brazil (Reports 010275), 1980 (Box 416)
  07690817
  94 p.
  Agriculture -- Brazil; Rice -- Brazil
- The significance of the potential for paddy rice production on the Amazon Varzea (Reports 010276), 1978 (Box 416)
  Rice -- Planting -- Brazil; Resource management -- Amazon River Region; Land use -- Amazon River Region
- A summary of the environmental impacts of forestry based activities in Amazonia (Reports 010277), undated (Box 416)
  Amazon development; Forests and forestry -- Amazon -- Brazil
- The Amazon forestry situation, development goals, and some key questions for future planning (Reports 010278), undated (Box 416)
- Agricultural development and environmental transformation in Terra Firme Amazonia: a neoclassical economic perspective (Reports 010279), undated (Box 416)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Brazil
- The economics of agricultural technology and environmental transformation in the Amazon (Reports 010280), undated (Box 416)
  Resource management -- Amazon River Region; Land use -- Amazon River Region
- Draft planning document for a resources and the environment program in Brazil (Reports 010281), 1979 (Box 417)
  Characterization of resource and environmental problem areas, review of social dimensions which aggravate environmental management, brief review of the activities of the international assistance organizations in the areas of resources and the environment,
  33 p. + attachments.
  Resources and the environment program in Brazil
  Environmental protection -- Brazil; Natural resources management -- Brazil
- Amazon resource development policy (Reports 010282), 1978 (Box 417)
  Draft report of a visit to the Amazon region intended to serve as a background paper to the anticipated program of the Resources and Environment Division of the Ford Foundation.
  Natural resources -- Amazon River Region
- Support to national agricultural research systems in Eastern and Southern Africa by international agricultural research institutions (Reports 010283), 1984 (Box 417)
  This is a report to the Ford Foundation's Eastern and Southern Africa Field Office.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, Southern; International agricultural research institutions
- Recommendations for an accelerated Jawar (sorghum) improvement program in West Pakistan (Reports 010284), 1966 (Box 417)
  06500341
  United Mexican States
  Strengthening agricultural institutions in wheat researchin West Pakistan.
  Accelerated crop improvement reports: no. 6
  Sorghum -- Research -- Pakistan; Crop improvement -- Pakistan; Agricultural development projects -- Pakistan; Agricultural assistance -- Pakistan
- Projections for wheat yields, wheat production and the main required inputs in order to reach self-sufficiency from 1968 onward (Reports 010285), 1966 (Box 417)
  6 p. + attach.
  Wheat -- Pakistan; Wheat -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan
- Projections for maize yields, maize production and the main required inputs (Reports 010286), 1966 (Box 417)
  Maize -- Pakistan; Maize -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan
- Telecommunications Task Force: meeting May 17 (Reports 010287), 1972 (Box 417)
  PAPER Conference (1972 May 17: New York, N.Y.)
  Telecommunication; Communication
- A brief review of Algerian cereal research and production (Reports 010288), 1974 (Box 417)
  Cereal products -- Algeria; Agriculture -- Algeria; Grain -- Algeria
- Status of progress in Tunisia's cereal research and production campaign (Reports 010289), 1974 (Box 417)
  Office of the Vice President/Middle East and Africa
  06800848
  Centro Internacional de Mejoramiento de Maiz y Trigo
  Wheat production program in North Africa.
  22 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Cereal products -- Tunisia; Wheat products -- Tunisia; Grain -- Tunisia; Agricultural development projects -- Tunisia; Agriculture and state -- Tunisia; Agricultural assistance -- Tunisia
- The Ford Foundation, CIMMYT Cereal Program in Tunisia: A review report submitted to the Ford Foundation (Reports 010290), 1977 (Box 417)
  14 p. + appendices.
  Grain -- Tunisia; Cereal products -- Tunisia
- The Ford Foundation-CIMMYT Centro Internacional de Mejoramiento de Maiz y Trigo Cereal Program in Algeria: a review report submitted to the Ford Foundation (Reports 010291), 1977 (Box 417)
  29 leaves + appendices.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Cereal products -- Algeria; Wheat products -- Algeria; Grain -- Algeria; Agricultural development projects -- Algeria; Agriculture and state -- Algeria; Agricultural assistance -- Algeria
- Confluent education: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 010292), 1974 (Box 417)
  154 p. + appendices.
  Alternative education; Educational change; Education -- Experimental methods
- River run deep, river run strong: confluence in humanistic education (Reports 010293), 1974 (Box 417)
  L76-54.
  242 p. + appendices.
  Confluent education
- Office of the Arts: Trustees Committee Meeting, June 25 (Reports 010294), 1975 (Box 417)
  L71-130
  Arts -- Endowments; Arts -- Endowments -- Finance -- Congresses; Arts -- Endowments -- Congresses
- Evaluation activities, education and research division (Reports 010295), 1976 (Box 417)
  L75-232.
  Education programs -- Evaluation
- Report and recommendations concerning the field of the social sciences in Greece (Reports 010296), 1978 (Box 418)
  L76-178.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Greece
- Assessing resource allocation and policy in educational decision-making: An interpretive application of some of the theories of Basil Bernstein (Reports 010297), 1976 (Box 418)
  Education -- Decision making
- Some thoughts on future policy oriented research on soil and water management in the Hills (Reports 010299), 1976 (Box 418)
  L76-198
  Soil management -- India; Water -- Management -- India
- Madhya Pradesh social forestry: A proposal for grant action (Reports 010300), 1976 (Box 418)
  Background information on Madhya Pradesh and a proposal for a forestry project.
  L76-118
  46 p. + appendices.
  Social forestry projects -- India -- Madhya Pradesh; Forests and forestry -- India -- Madhya Pradesh
- The search for national integration in Africa (Reports 010301), 1971 (Box 418)
  L76-57.
  Ethnic conflict -- Africa, Sub-Saharan
- Ford Foundation's program regarding Japan, Feb. (Reports 010302), 1980 (Box 418)
  Philanthropy -- Japan
- The study and teaching of international relations in Brazil: a survey and a proposal (Reports 010303), 1976 (Box 418)
  L76-85.
  International relations -- Brazil
- A proposed plan for the development of the Bangladesh Agricultural Development Corporation Seed Multiplication Farms (Reports 010304), 1976 (Box 418)
  Discussion of the value of seed multiplication farms in Bangladesh.
  Seed technology -- Bangladesh; Seeds -- Bangladesh
- Population and family planning in India (Reports 010305), 1976 (Box 418)
  L76-301.
  Birth control -- India -- Population
- Comparing television to other agencies of socialization: University of Wisconsin (Reports 010306), 1976 (Box 418)
  L76-97.
  Socialization -- Television; Television -- Socialization
- The analysis of social policy: An account of visits to the USA, January-March and (Reports 010307), 1976 (Box 418)
  L76-61
  27 p. + attachments.
  Social policy -- Analysis
- Office of the Arts: Trustees Committee Meeting, December 11 (Reports 010308), 1975 (Box 418)
  "Agenda: Meeting of Trustee Arts committee, December 11, 1975: 1. Proposed programs for development of talent and art forms, 2. Discussion of state and community arts councils and possible Foundation support for their work, 3. Supplemental report on cas
  [i], 16 p. -- 28 cm.
- The office of communications and public information: statement of mission, implementation strategies, recommendations (Reports 010309), 1976 (Box 418)
- Curriculum and program design for training basic health services personnel (Reports 010310), 1976 (Box 418)
  Public health -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria
- Some thoughts on the state of economics in China and the possible role of foundations in related exchanges (Reports 010311), 1979 (Box 418)
  Letter to Mr. John Bresnan.
  Economics -- China; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- China
- Report on visits to Chinese faculties of law and schools of politics and law (Reports 010312), 1982 (Box 418)